manfrotto.us 2018-08-19

# Privacy

### _WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY_

* updated to Reg. UE 2016/679 (GDPR)

This page describes the guidelines for processing personal data through this website, in relation to users who consult and / or interact with the services provided on this website.

### 1\. DATA CONTROLLER

The Data Controllers for the information provided through this website are as follows:  
\- Vitecgroup Italia Spa  
\- Vitec Imaging Solutions Spa

Both companies are based in Italy, Via Valsugana 100 - 36022 Cassola (VI) email [privacy.imaging@vitecgroup.com](mailto:%20privacy.imaging@vitecgroup.com) (as well as the local distributor: Vitec Imaging Distribution Inc.)

### 2\. TYPES OF DATA PROCESSED, PURPOSE AND LAWFULNESS OF PROCESSING

### 2.1 Data provided voluntarily by the User for the Services requested 

If the User, to access the services / information offered, voluntarily provides some of his personal data, collected through appropriate formats on the website, this action involves the acquisition of such data by the Data Controller in order to provide the requested services. 

The services provided through the website may include inviting users to register for newsletters, responding to product enquiries, products sales, collecting job applications or other services not listed here.

Some of the data requested through the website must be captured in order for the service to be provided, and are indicated with an asterisk. Other data is purely optional and may be provided by the User to allow a more complete and personalized service or, subject to prior consent in the cases governed by current legislation, to analyse personal interests and information or habits or consumption choices. 

In particular:

**Registration to the website / Participation in a blog:** identification data such as name, surname, email address, as well as other optional personal information relating to the User are collected. If you register through the social media profiles (Facebook, YouTube, Instagram, etc.) information on these profiles can be retrieved. 

**E-commerce:** data relating to the purchase, delivery and payment of the product / service is collected, as well as additional optional personal information relating to the User.

**Newsletter:** identification data such as name, surname, e-mail address, as well as other optional personal information concerning the User are collected.

**Open applications / CV:** data necessary for the evaluation of the application (identification data, curriculum information and professional information) is collected.

**Guarantee extension:** User identification and product data is collected, as well as additional optional personal information concerning the User.

**Web Chat:** User identification data is collected, for assistance during the purchase phase, as well as to provide information on products. 

**Prize competition/ other promotions:** User's identification data for the management of these marketing initiatives is collected.

**Marketing / Commercial communications / Analysis of habits and consumption choices:** with the prior consent of the User, personal data may be collected for the aforementioned purposes.

Accordingly, the purposes of processing such data, based on the services requested, are as follows:

  * execution of the service requested by the User;
  * execution of the contractual relationship with the User and any related contractual obligations (e.g. e-commerce: orders and payments management, product delivery) and Customer Service management and information to the User;
  * execution of legal matters, administrative and accounting obligations related to the request of the User's services or contractual obligations (e.g. e-commerce);
  * communication with the customer regarding the requested service;
  * marketing and sending of related commercial communications, analysis of personal interests and information or habits or consumption choices and prior consent of the interested party;
  * in some case it may be necessary to process the prevention of fraud and the abuse to the detriment of this website;
  * Management of any Curriculum Vitae (CVs) collected through the website. 

The legal basis for the processing of data is:

  * fulfilment of contractual obligations, if and as requested, by the User; and
  * the consent of the interested party.

### 2.2 Navigation Data

In addition to the following regarding cookies, the computer systems and software procedures used to operate this website acquire, during their normal operation, some personal data whose transmission is implicit in the use of Internet communication protocols. This is information that is not collected to be associated with identified interested parties, but which by their very nature could, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to be identified.

This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of the computers used by the Users who connect to the website, the addresses in the Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) notation, the requested resources, the time of the request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server (success, error, etc.) and other parameters related to the operating system and the user's IT environment.

This data is used to obtain anonymous statistical information on the use of the website and to check its correct functioning.

The data could be used to identify responsibility in the event of possible IT crimes to the detriment of the website. The website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). To this regard, see the Google cookie policy for Google Analytics.

The purposes for processing such data are therefore to:

  * allow the website to function and perform the services requested by the User;
  * monitor and improve the operation of the website;
  * derive and use statistical information on the use of the website;
  * ascertaining responsibility in the event that a possible cyber security criminal act has been committed.

The lawfulness of the processing of such data is therefore the legitimate interest of the holder for the performance and improvement of the services provided by the website.

### 2.3 Cookies and tracking

A cookie and similar technologies are small bits of information used to store technical and / or personal details on the computer, identify users of a service and enable certain features. The Data Controller and its partners for technical, statistical and / or profiling reasons use these cookies.

It is possible to configure the browser in such a way that the acceptance of cookies is, in principle, denied or the notification is received before a cookie is stored.

The lawfulness of the processing is therefore the legitimate interest of the owner in the case of technical cookies and the consent of the person concerned for profiling cookies.

For more information on the cookies used by the Services and on how to refuse them, visit the Technical Cookie Policy accessible by clicking here.

### 2.4 Geo-location

The website will be able to track data relating to the User's location in cases where they have been expressly authorized based on the privacy settings of the account, the applications and browsers installed and the devices in use. This location information is used to improve the User experience and the overall quality of the Services.

### 3\. COMMUNICATION OF DATA TO THIRD PARTIES

### 3.1 Data provided voluntarily by the User (Registration to the Website, Newsletter subscription, Request for contacts or information, Management of job applications, E-commerce, etc.)

The personal data provided by the User is managed by the internal subjects of the Data Controllers (collaborators and employees), based on their skills and within the scope of their duties and / or any contractual obligations. 

Some data may be communicated for the fulfilment of the purposes indicated to: Group companies (www.vitecgroup.com); external subjects / companies to whom the communication of personal Data is necessary or functional for the execution of the requested service or management of the contractual relationship with the interested party (marketing consulting, strategic, IT, hosting companies or managing services for account of the holders, transport company for the shipment / transport of purchased products or sending of documentation or material, customs, insurance companies, sales network, recruitment company for the management of applications) in the manner and for the purposes described above, under the control of Data Controller.

### 3.2 Geolocation navigation data

Navigation / geolocation data can be communicated to companies that provide IT services

### 3.3 Data circulation

We do not pass any of their personal data to outside organisations, including subsidiary companies, and/or individuals, other than the data processors specified above, except with their express consent.

### 4\. TRANSFER TO THIRD COUNTRIES

The personal data provided by the User and the other types of data processed and browsing data may be processed or transferred to countries outside the EU, for the purposes indicated above, in compliance with current legislation regarding the transfer of data to third countries pursuant to article 44 and following of the EU Reg. 2016/670 (GDPR) and of the local regulations in force.

### 5\. METHOD OF PROCESSING

Personal data is processed using computer tools, and in compliance with the confidentiality and protection measures required by current legislation. Specific security measures are in place to prevent data loss, illicit or incorrect use, and unauthorized access.

### 6\. DATA CONSERVATION PERIOD

Data provided by the User: personal data provided by the User is kept for the period necessary for the execution of the indicated purposes and, if necessary for fulfilment of contractual, tax or, legal obligations (i.e. e-commerce purchase Data) for the period provided for by the local current legislation. In particular: Contractual / fiscal data (sale of products / services): ten years (or different deadlines dependent on local regulations) from the last use or interruption of the Services. Data on applications and curricula two years from receipt of the data provided by the User (or different deadline provided for by local regulations), except in the case of company inclusion. Newsletter subscription data: The newsletter subscription data are kept for the entire period in which the interested party wishes to remain subscribed to the newsletter and until the newsletter is revoked

###  7\. AUTOMATED PROCESSES

Automated decision-making processes (e.g. cookies) can be carried out for website functions and / or automated processes aimed at analysing the user's habits, choices, browsing methods, through cookies or services of third parties, with the consent of the interested party as below specified.

### 8\. DATA PROVISION AND CONSEQUENCES OF FAILURE TO PROVIDE

Apart from that specified for navigation data, the User is free to provide personal data contained in the request forms of the website services. Failure to provide the data required as mandatory, however, does not allow the execution of the requested service. Failure to provide the data indicated as optional instead could result in the provision of an incomplete service and the inability to carry out further activities of the Data Controller.

### 9\. RIGHTS OF INTERESTED PERSONS, FACULTY TO PROPOSE THE COMPLAINT AND REVOCATION OF CONSENT

Each User for whom personal data have been collected, according to the methods described in this Policy, have the right at any time to request, if the conditions of law exist, access to their personal data, rectification, cancellation, the limitation of the same, to oppose the processing and to exercise the right to data portability.

The interested party has the right to revoke at any time the consent given to the processing of data, without prejudice to the lawfulness of the process based on the consent given before the revocation. To exercise the rights provided by the current legislation on the protection of personal data and to know the complete list of External Data Processor of the processing appointed for each area and activity or for information on the transfer of data to countries outside the EU and related guarantees you can write to [privacy.imaging@vitecgroup.com](mailto:privacy.imaging@vitecgroup.com) and distributor's address, 10 Mountainview Road, Suite 320 South Upper Saddle River, NJ 07458 USA. We will process your request as soon as possible, in any case, within a maximum of 30 days. 

The Data Subject also has the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority, in particular in the Member State where he resides habitually or in the Member State in which he works or where the alleged violation took place

###  10\. MINORS, VERIDICITY OF DATA INSERTED AND USER OBLIGATIONS

This website does not address its services to children and minors, as defined in local law. By registering with one of the Services and accepting this Privacy Policy, you confirm that you are of the required age in your country to be able to sign a contract, or request the services provided. In addition/alternatively, the child/minor confirms that he previously obtained consent from the parents / guardians required in the country, where applicable. In any case, we reserve the right to contact the User and verify the possession of these prerequisites and, in the event that these are found to be lacking, the right to suspend or eliminate the account or interrupt or suspend the services provided.

### 11\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 

This Privacy Policy will be updated periodically in case of changes to services provided, or regulatory obligations. Please therefore consult this page often, referring to the date of the last modification indicated at the bottom.

Date of the latest update: 07/2018
